<resources>
    <string name="app_name">StoryApp</string>
    <string-array name="title_story">
        <item>The Foolish Fish</item>
        <item>The Golden Egg</item>
        <item>The Golden Swan</item>
        <item>The Fragrance</item>
        <item>The Greedy Dog</item>
        <item>The Holy Snake</item>
        <item>The Ignorant Man</item>
        <item>The Iron Box</item>
        <item>The Judge Monkey</item>
        <item>The Lamb and The Wolf</item>
        <item>The Magic Pot</item>
        <item>The Perfect Palace</item>

    </string-array>

    <string-array name="detail_story">

        <item>In a huge pond, there lived many fish. They were arrogant and never listened to anyone. In this pond, there also lived a kind-hearted crocodile.
He advised the fish, “It does not pay to be arrogant and overconfident. It could be your downfall." But the fish never listened to him. “There is that crocodile, advising us again," they would say.
One afternoon, the crocodile was resting beside a stone near the pond, when two fishermen stopped there to drink water.
The fishermen noticed that the pond had many fish. “Look! This pond is full of fish. Let’s come here tomorrow with our fishing net," said one of them. “I am surprised we have not seen this place before!" exclaimed the other.
The crocodile heard all this. When the fishermen left, he slowly slipped into the pond and went straight to the fish. “You all had better leave this pond before dawn. Early morning those two fishermen are going to come to this pond with their net," warned the crocodile.
</item>
        <item>Haria, a poor barber lived alone in his small hut. He was dedicated to his work. And whatever he earns was enough to fulfill his needs.One evening, after returning from work, Haria was hungry. “What shall I cook tonight?" he thought. Just then he heard a hen clucking outside his hut. “That hen would make a great feast for me," thought Haria and prepared to catch the hen.With a little effort he was able to catch the hen. As he was about to kill the hen, it squeaked, “Please do not kill me, O kind man! I will help you." Haria stopped. Though he was surprised that the hen spoke, he asked, “How can you help me?"
“If you spare my life, I will lay a golden egg everyday for you," said the hen. Haria’s eyes got widened in delight. Haria was surprised to hear this promise. “A golden egg! That too everyday! But why should I believe you? You might be lying," said Haria. “If I do not lay a golden egg tomorrow, you can kill me," said the hen. After this promise, Haria spared the hen and waited for the next day.
The next morning, Haria found a golden egg lying outside his hut and the hen sitting beside it. “It is true! You really can lay a golden egg!" exclaimed Haria with great delight. He did not reveal this incident to any one, fearing that others would catch the hen.
</item>
        <item>Long time ago, there lived a King. He was lazy and liked all the comforts of life. He never carried out his duties as a King. “Our King does not take care of our needs. He also ignores the affairs of his kingdom." The people complained.One day, the King went into the forest to hunt. After having wandered for quite sometime, he became thirsty. To his relief, he spotted a lake. As he was drinking water, he suddenly saw a golden swan come out of the lake and perch on a stone. “Oh! A golden swan. I must capture it," thought the King.
But as soon as he held his bow up, the swan disappeared. And the King heard a voice, “I am the Golden Swan. If you want to capture me, you must come to heaven."
Surprised, the King said, “Please show me the way to heaven." “Do good deeds, serve your people and the messenger from heaven would come to fetch you to heaven," replied the voice.
The selfish King, eager to capture the Swan, tried doing some good deeds in his Kingdom. “Now, I suppose a messenger will come to take me to heaven," he thought. But, no messenger came.
The King then disguised himself and went out into the street. There he tried helping an old man. But the old man became angry and said, “You need not try to help. I am in this miserable state because of out selfish King. He has done nothing for his people."
</item>
        <item>In a small town lived a wealthy merchant. He was very kind and charitable. He had a son, who had unfortunately fallen into a bad company. Many times the merchant advised his son not to go with the bad company. But all in vain. “Please, do not advise me what to do, my father. I know what is good for me and I know what to do," said the son.One day, a great saint came to the town. The merchant went to the saint, sought his blessings and said, “My spoilt son is the only cause of my worry. Please help me."
After few minutes of contemplation, the saint replied, “Send your son to my Ashram tomorrow morning. I will talk to him."
Next morning, the merchant sent his son to the Ashram of the saint. There the saint asked the son to pluck a flower of rose from the garden of the Ashram. The son did as asked by the saint. Then the saint asked the son,"Smell it and feel its fragrance, my son." The boy did so. Then saint showed the son a sack of wheat said, “Keep the rose near the sack." The boy followed the instructions.
After an hour, the saint asked the boy to smell the rose again. “How does it smell now?" the saint asked the boy. The boy smelt the rose and said, “It smells as good as before." Then the saint said, “Hmm! Now keep the rose near this sack of jaggery." The boy did so.
After an hour, the saint asked the boy to smell the rose again. “Is there any change in the fragrance?" the saint asked the boy. “No. it smells as fresh as before," replied the boy.
</item>
        <item>Once there lived a dog. He was very greedy. There were many times that he had to pay for his greed. Each time the dog promised himself, “I have learnt my lesson. Now I will never be greedy again." But he soon forgot his promises and was as greedy as ever.
One afternoon, the dog was terribly hungry. He decided to go look for something to eat. Just outside his house, there was a bridge. “I will go and look for food on the other side of the bridge. The food there is definitely better," he thought to himself.
He walked across the wooden bridge and started sniffing around for food. Suddenly, he spotted a bone lying at a distance. “Ah, I am in luck. This looks a delicious bone," he said.
Without wasting any time, the hungry dog picked up the bone and was just about to eat it, when he thought, “Somebody might see here with this bone and then I will have to share it with them. So, I had better go home and eat it." Holding the bone in his mouth, he ran towards his house.
While crossing the wooden bridge, the dog looked down into the river. There he saw his own reflection. The foolish dog mistook it for another dog. “There is another dog in the water with bone in its mouth," he thought. Greedy, as he was, he thought, “How nice it would be to snatch that piece of bone as well. Then, I will have two bones."
</item>
        <item>Long ago, in a small village lived Vishnudutta, a poor Brahmin farmer. He worked hard but was not able to earn much. His son, Somadutta was always asking for more money. “Be satisfied with what you have, my son," Vishnudutta would say.
One day, Vishnudutta was resting in his field after work. Suddenly, he noticed a snake on the nearby mount. On seeing Vishnudutta, the snake coiled and sat up with a raised hood. “It looks so calm and peaceful. May be it is a deity," thought Vishnudutta. He brought a bowl of milk from his house and offered it to the snake.
Next morning, when Vishnudutta came to collect the bowl, he found a gold coin in it. “I am sure this is a holy snake," he thought. After that it became a regular practice for him to offer prayers and milk to the snake. And every morning he got a gold coin in the bowl near the mount. This made Vishnudutta a rich man.Once, while Vishnudutta was away, his son Somadutta had to keep the bowl of milk near the snake. As usual, after some time, there was a gold coin in the bowl near the mount. Somadutta thought. “I guess there is a treasure of gold coins beneath this mount. If I can kill this snake and dig under the mount, I will get all the gold!" With gold on his mind, Somadutta tried to kill the snake. The snake bit Somadutta and managed to escape.
</item>
        <item>There was a village in a kingdom. There was living a milkman. His name was Deenu. He had built his hut far away from his village, in the woods. He loved the quietness of the woods rather than the noisy atmosphere of the village. He lived in his hut with his two cows. He fed them well and took proper care of them. Everyday he took the two cows to a nearby lake to bath them. The two cows gave more milk. With the milk that the two cows gave, he earned enough money to live happily.
Deenu was an honest man. Though he was content, at times he would be restless. “There is so much wrong and evil in this world. Is there nobody to guide the people?" this thought made his sad every now and then.One evening, the ignorant man, Deenu was returning home after selling milk in the village. He saw a saint sitting under a tree and meditating. He slowly walked up to him and waited for the saint to open his eyes. He was happy to be with the saint for some time. He decided to wait there itself till the saint opened his eyes After a while, the saint slowly opened his eyes. He was surprised to see a man patiently sitting beside him.
“What do you want?" asked the saint humbly.

“I want to know what the path to Truth and Piety is? Where shall I find Honesty?" asked Deenu.
The saint smiled and said, “Go to the pond nearby and ask the fish the same question. She will give you the answer."
Then as asked to do, the ignorant man, Deenu went to the nearby pond and asked the same question to the fish. The fish said, “O kind man! First, bring me some water to drink." Deny was surprised. He said, “You live in water. But you still want water to drink? How strange!"
</item>
        <item>Mohan Das was the son of a rich businessman. When his father died, Mohan Das was left with an iron box with valuables in it. One day, Mohan Das had to go to the city on some work. So, he took the iron box and handed it over to his moneylender friend. His name was Ramasewak.
“Please keep this box. My father gave it to me. I will return from city after few days and collect it from you," said Mohan Das to Ramasewak.
“You do not have to worry. I will keep this box safely," said Ramasewak.
Mohan Das started off his journey happily. He knew that his valuable iron box was safe with Ramasewak. A few days later he returned. He went to his friend Ramasewak and asked for the iron box. Ramasewak pretended to look a little surprised, “Oh, the iron box! The rats ate it up. I just could not stop them," he said.
Mohan Das realized that his friend had become greedy and dishonest. Ramasewak was trying to cheat him. Being an intelligent man, he kept quite. “I must figure out a way to get my iron box back from Ramasewak," thought Mohan Das.
Next day, Mohan Das went to Ramasewak and said, “Friend! Can you send your son with me? I need someone to look after my property."
Ramasewak thought for a while. He brooded. “Mohan Das seems to be a fool. May be he will reward my son for looking after his property," thought Ramasewak. Then, immediately he agreed and sent his son with Mohan Das.</item>
        <item>Once upon a time, two cats were passing through a street. Suddenly they spotted a loaf of bread lying beneath a tree. Both pounced upon it and caught the loaf at the same time. “It is mine. I saw it first," claimed one cat. While the other said, “I pounced upon it first and so it belongs to me." After having fought for a while, one cat said, “Let us divide it into two and take one piece each." “Indeed, a good idea," said the other cat. “But how do we divide it now?"
A monkey sitting on the branch of the tree had watched all that happened between the two cats. “That loaf of bread looks good. I could do with it myself," he thought. Slowly he came down from the tree and walked up to the confused cats.
“Yes, my dear friends! Can I help you?" asked the monkey. The cats told the monkey what the problem was and said, “Why do not you be the judge between us?" When the monkey nodded, the cats said, “Please divide this loaf for us."
The clever monkey smilingly broke the bread into two pieces. But one piece was a little bigger that the other. “OH no! I will take a little bite of this bigger piece to make both equal," said the monkey, slyly. He took a bite from the bigger piece. But, he had taken a big bite. “Uh oh! Now it has become smaller than the other piece. I will just have to take a little bite from this piece now," said the clever monkey.
The Judge Monkey took another bite. The two cats sat in front of the monkey, seeing the loaf of bread they had found getting smaller and smaller. When the whole loaf was eaten by the monkey, the monkey said, “I am sorry. I was really difficult to divide that loaf. I must be going now." And the monkey jumped onto the tree and was gone. “If only we had not quarreled among ourselves, we would have remained united and we need not have to go to the monkey and to become hungry now," said the two cats.
</item>
        <item>Once there was a naughty lamb. His mother always loved her child so much that she worried about the safety of the child. His mother always warned him, “Be careful! You must not go into the forest. Wild animals live in there. They may threaten you. Sometimes they would eat you." But the mischievous lamb never listened. The lamb casually went into the forest and played there for a long time till it turned dark in the evening.One day, as usual the lamb wandered far off into the forest. There he saw a spring. “I am thirsty. Let me drink some water," he thought. He decided to take water from the spring for his thirsty. While the lamb was drinking water in the spring, a wolf watched from behind a tree.

“A lamb! My lucky day!" the wolf thought, approaching the lamb. The lamb was not aware of the wolf for some time. There was no one besides these two animals to save the lamb from the wolf.
“You know this forest belongs only to wild animals like me. Why have you come in here to take water from this spring?" asked the wolf.
The lamb knew that wolves were dangerous animals. “Mother has warned me about wolves. I am sure this fellow wants to eat me for his lunch. This fellow is ferocious. I must escape from this animal," he thought.
The wolf continued, “You are also dirtying water. How will I drink this polluted water now?"
“But the spring flows from where you are standing down to where I am standing, Sir!" said the lamb, in a meek voice. The wolf was surprised to hear such an intelligent answer from the lamb. But the wolf was just looking for an excuse to kill the lamb. “How dare you argue with me? I think you are the same lamb who had abused me last year," the wolf shouted.
“Last year? Bur Sir, I was not even born then!" the lamb squeaked. The lamb feared that the wolf was looking after a pretext to kill the lamb. The lamb became cautious of its words and gestures. This way both the lamb and the wolf talked to each other cautiously.
The lamb heard some woodcutters. They were coming the way in which the lamb and the wolf were standing. “"If I can keep talking to this wolf for a little while longer, the woodcutters will be here. They will chase him away," thought the clever lamb. So, he said, “Mr. Wolf, you are right. I have dirtied the water. But, I did not mean to upset you."
</item>
        <item>Once upon a time a farmer, Gopi, lived in a village. He had few acres of land. One hot afternoon, the poor farmer was digging his field. All of a sudden, his spade hit something. Then he continued his digging. “It is a big metal pot," said Gopi. It was big enough to boil rice for more than hundred people. “It does not seem to be of any use to me. I will dig deeper. May be I will find something else," thought Gopi. He continued to dig.
After he had dug for a long time, Gopi felt tired. “It is of no use. There is nothing in this field" he thought. Then at once, he threw the spade into the pot in frustration and sat under a tree to take rest for a while.
After a while, when he got up to leave, he could not believe his eyes. There were one hundred spades in the pot. “This is a magical pot. I will put this mango inside the pot and see what happens," Gopi thought. Then Gopi put a mango into the pot. To his astonishment, he found one hundred mangoes in the pot. Gopi carried the pot to his home and kept in a secret place so that no one would become aware of it.
After that, he put many things in that and everything became hundred folds. With that pot, he became a rich man. The King came to know of the pot and its whereabouts. The King was curious to know about it and he was a greedy King. “I want to find out the secret of the magical pot. If it is valuable, it should be in the King treasury," the King thought. Then at once, the King ordered his men to bring the farmer and his pot.When the magic pot was brought to the King’s chamber, he did not know what to do. The King thought, “Let me see what is there inside this pot which makes this pot so magical?" He peered inside. Inadvertently, he slipped and fell inside the pot. When he climbed out of the magic pot, he was shocked to find that there were one hundred Kings.
All the kings then started to climb the throne. They fought among themselves and died. The magic pot lay in the King’s treasury. “The foolish King took away the magic pot from me out of curiosity and eventually he died. This magic pot has killed the King himself," said the farmer and he to be safe left the magic pot at the treasury of the King itself.
</item>
        <item>Thousands of years ago, there lived a King. His people loved him since he looked after their needs well. At the end of every month, he would invite some noble men of his Kingdom to analyze his work and advised him.The King built many things. Every year he would rebuild his palace and every time it looked better that before. “Marvelous! Unmatched!!" the couriers would praise and the King would feel elated.
One day the King thought, “This year, I will build the perfect palace, with all comforts. It should be praised not only within my kingdom, but also by the people of the neighboring states."
The next day, the King worked out a perfect design for his perfect palace. After finalizing it, he handed it over to the builders and masons. In about a month, the perfect palace of the King’s dream was ready. The King invited noblemen of his kingdom, as well as the neighboring states, to get their opinions about the palace.
Unbelievable! Indeed, it is a perfect palace," cheered the noblemen in unison. But a saint standing in the corner was silent.
The King wondered why the saint was silent, when everyone was praising his palace. He walked up to the saint and said, “Please tell, O Saint, why you are silent. Is not my palace perfect?"

The Saint replied in a calm voice, “Dear King! Your palace is strong and will last forever. It is beautiful but not perfect, since the people living in it are mortals. They are not permanent. Your palace will live forever but not the people in it. That is why I am silent. Man is born with empty hands and so does he die."

The King thanked the saint for his wise words and never tried to build a perfect palace again.

</item>


    </string-array>

</resources>
